Mohammad Rafi'ul Haq

Hyderabad, Telangana, India



mdrafiulhaq@gmail.com



+919949563502



linkedin.com/in/mohammadrafiulhaq

Summary

As an Admin & HR professional, I am committed to improving individual, Team and Organizational performance by managing and developing Administration and HR activities that adds value and impact to bottom line business results. Able to deliver all aspects of Administration on both functional and operational levels through sound interpersonal communication, organizational and leadership abilities.

I have a successful record of providing an excellent standard of administration services to Business. Identifying and implementing cost reduction / cost rationalization and process improvement initiatives. During my career I have gained an excellent reputation for being approachable and empathetic as well as eloquent and persuasive.

I will bring fresh ideas, new perspectives and a diversity of experiences in key Administration and HR areas, such as Facility & Office Management, People & Talent Management, Time & Attendance Management, Meeting & Diary Management, and Cash & Vendor Management.

I work confidently and efficiently with various Spreadsheets, Office Suites, HRMS, HCM and Payroll Suites, e-mail and intranet systems. Particular skilled at Workforce planning, mapping and budgeting, HRIS, Payroll Submissions, Book Keeping, Drafting and Formatting, Requirements Analysis, Elicitation, Maintaining databases and Control Sheets, carrying out reference checks and coordinating interviews.

After acquiring 6+ years' experience in Administration and HR in a Retail and Service industries, I am now ready to join a reputable company which has a reputation for looking after its employees.

Experience



Subject Matter Expert VCS

Amazon.com

Sep 2022 - Present (1 year)

Responsible for mentoring, training, guiding newly hired agents.

Ensuring accurate representation of expertise prior to the distribution of solutions by inspecting and validating CS handling and processes.

Recognizing quality concerns contributing to poor CS and communicate these to CS Management and appropriate department liasons.



Virtual Customer Service Agent(VCS) for North America Business Unit

Amazon

May 2021 - Present (2 years 4 months)

Empowered and expected to think like owner(Jeff Bezos).

Working towards a single goal: to deliver the best possible support experience to the customers.

Solving problems the first time so that customers have an effortless experience every time.

Building on Amazon's global mission of being the 'Earth's most customer-centric company',

RT. Administration Officer - Central Region

REDTAG

Jan 2018 - Jun 2018 (6 months)

Responsible for the Plan, Organize, Implement and Execute robust Admin & HR functions across the region in accordance with the organization's vision and mission statement.

Responsible for providing complex administrative support with ability to foreseeing and anticipating the needs of the Executive, Office and Organization to optimize their time and taking a can-do role to anticipate, identify and initiate/facilitate thoughtful solutions.

Plan, budget, direct and coordinate the Maintenance team and activities in the Region. Maintain the Petty Cash system, approval process, cash disbursements and funding requests.

Requisition for Office Supplies on monthly basis. Record and Maintain Vehicle Fuel/Repair Expenses Control Sheet, Maintenance Records and Registration/insurance Renewal.

Managing and developing administrative staff to ensure smooth operations and the provision of accurate and timely information. Leading them in handling requests related to travel arrangements, expense reimbursements, stationary, payroll, employee information, time and attendance, incorporate changes after promotions and transfers in the HR system.

Organize, direct, and follow up on all administrative and HR activities assigned, ensuring all work is done accurately and on a timely basis.

Monitor the implementation of the regional manpower plan and budget at regular intervals, to ensure compliance across all shops in the region.

Meeting with Area Managers to develops strategies to achieve required staffing levels. Preparing Interview material, organizing recruiting events and contributing to local transfer recruiting activities such as telephone screening, face-to-face interviews with candidates. Provide administrative and documentation support to the teams to ensure effective implementation of standards, structures and processes across the employee life-cycle (hire to retire).

RT. Regional Coordinator (Admin & HR)

REDTAG

Sep 2014 - Dec 2017 (3 years 4 months)

RT. Regional Coordinator (Admin & HR)

REDTAG

May 2013 - Sep 2014 (1 year 5 months)

Khdanis Coordinator

Kholani's Group Jun 2012 - May 2013 (1 year)

Education

Osmania University

Master of Business Administration (M.B.A.), Retail Management 2010 - 2012

Osmania University

Bachelor of Commerce - BCom, Accounting and Finance 2006 - 2009

Licenses & Certifications

Aviation Security Awareness - GMR Group

GHIAL/AVSEC/batch-68-09/2119

- NHCPS® 2 CME Credit Certificate™ for CPR, AED & First Aid Save a Life Certifications by NHCPS
 Issued Aug 2018 Expires Aug 2020
- EF SET® Certificate™ English CEFR Level C1 (Advanced) EF Education First
- Business Process Automation airSlate

Skills

Self-Management • Problem Solving • Organization Skills • Communication • Written Communication • Office Administration • Team Management • Human Resource Management • Cost Accounting • Sales

Honors & Awards

- 3 x Well Done Card (Expenses Reimbursements on time and Maintenance) Area Manager. & Maintenance Manager REDTAG Central Region
 Jun 2016
- 2 x Well Done Card (Outstanding work in Attendance & Payroll) Mr.Sameer Lakadawala, Regional Manager REDTAG Central Region
 Jul 2016
- **iLead with CHRO** Mr.Ashutosh Labroo, CHRO BMA International Group GCC Feb 2017
- ilnspire with General Manager Mr.Imtiyaz Khan, GM REDTAG KSA Apr 2018

